ADEEL WILLAYT ALI (CCNA,CCNP,CCDP,HCNA)

Network, System, Security, VM, Azure Administrator

Mobile: +966 – 54 – 6411980

Email Address: adeelwillayt@gmail.com

Location: Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

OBJECTIVE

Over 9 years of experience in IT Network System Security, Designing, Implementing and Troubleshooting performs network administration & planning for all aspects of all IT-network infrastructure to include network equipment, servers, and software applications. Brings in reliable, durable, and cost-effective solutions for all IT related needs.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Experience with Cisco networking equipment Full knowledge of VTP servers
- Experience in Microsoft Azure technologies and products Active Directory, Office 365
- Deploying VMs into Virtual Networks. Router IOS backup and recovery. Routing protocol configurations and checking CDP configurations. Full command in inter-VLAN routing
- Technical knowledge of routing protocols OSPF, EIGRP, RIP AND RIP v2.
- Responsible for the regular back up and restoration of all critical assets.

- Primary assistance and troubleshooting on IT platform
- Understanding of DHC Knowledge implementing of Security, Network and Wireless Installation
- requirements and guidelines. Familiar with both MLS and Layer 2 switches and
- Responsible for troubleshooting of networking equipment. Full command on CISCO IOS commands
- Good knowledge of Standard Access List, Extended Access List and VLANS.
- Full knowledge of preventing loops using STP, PVST, RSTP.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

INTERNATIONAL HOSPITAL CONSTRUCTION COMPANY (IHCC)

IT System, Network and Security Engineer 2021– Current



- Responsible for managing company IT infrastructure, and network operation center, enterprise
- software, application software and other IT Infrastructure.
- Managing SOPHOS firewalls, Antivirus and VPN.
- Managing Active Directory Domain, DNS, and MS Exchange 2013 and 2016.
- Troubleshooting mail flow issues and monitoring exchange service health and availability.
- Managing Corporate Switching and Routing networks and implement new devices.
- Configure and manage Veeam Backup.
- Accountable for design, creation, and implementation of IT & Systems.
- Designing and implementing company's wireless networks.
- Supporting remotely for site office escalated issues.
- configuring and managing light beam Nano station for Earth cam and cctv
- Video Editing in coral studio

KING KHALID MILITARY ACADEMY

Network/Server/Security and Data Center Admin

2013 - 2021

- Responsible for Network/Server/Security and Data Center monitor and configure management.
- Managing SOPHOS Proxy server, Cisco firewall, Firepower, Symantec and currently working on (VDI, hyper V, VM ware, Citirx Wi-Fi, Active Directory Email Exchange server, solar Wind, Cisco Prime, Adobe Photoshop, L O Drawing, Putty and Digital signage).
- Oversees the day-to-day operation of computer, network, and server including hardware/software support, training, and special projects, Analyzes and troubleshoots the problem. Network designing
- Provides high levels of customer service when responding and resolving to issues
- Provides training and managing technical support team with network troubleshooting, upgrading.
- Experience of 8 years in all Cisco products Router, Switch, firewall, WIFI devices
- Provide support on achieving ISO 27001 Certification
- Responsible for back up data Documents system changes and ensuring configuration documents are updated with each change.
- Assist the media (PR) department of the Academy in its tasks or projects
- Responsible for keeping the company interlinked with social websites

FAHAD STUDIO AND LABORATORY

Graphic Designer

2009-2012

- Gaining Adobe Photoshop expertise
- Design the pictures with customization
- Editing the pictures according to the requirement
- Concept Creating Work

QUALIFICATIONS AND CERTIFICATIONS

Certifications:

- O CompTIA Network+ Securing TCP/IP (2021)
- o CCDP | Cisco Certified Design Professional (2018)
- o HCNA Routing and Switching (2017)
- CCNP Routing and Switching (2016)
- o CCNA Routing and Switching (2014)
- o CCNA Discovery (2013)

British Council

o IELTS (2015)

Institute of Computer Technology

o Adobe Photoshop

Education:

BA (Honors) - Business Management – (2016)

Binary University of Management & Entrepreneurship

Advanced Diploma in Business – (2015)

Institute of Commercial Management (England)

Diploma in Business – (2014)

Institute of Commercial Management (England)

SKILLS AND INTEREST

- Microsoft Office
- Computer Hardware Settings
- Excellent in team work and planning for the new tasks
- Good presentation, Communication & interpersonal skills working
- Excellent knowledge of business communication skills, project management
- Strategies, business tactics and strategies, fundamentals of economics and accounting

- Football
- Reading
- Traveling
- Internet Browsing

